

## Sayantani Seal

Present Address: 3/156, Gandhi Colony

Kolkata - 700092

Permanent Address: 28/A Doctor Jagabandhu Lane, Kolkata - 700012

7044093357

sayantanisil43@gmail.com

#### **About**

Experienced Social Media Manager and PR Head experience in managing premium handcrafted products for The Burlap People, a leading handcrafted bag manufacturing company based in Kolkata, India. Skilled in SEO, SMM, SEM, Podcasting, Graphic Designing, Video Editing, UI UX, and many more, and have won numerous awards for executing successful branding and advertising campaigns

# **Objective**

To obtain a challenging position as a Social Media Manager or Public Relations Head, where my creativity, marketing skills, and experience in managing premium handcrafted products can be utilized to enhance the brand image and drive sales.

## **Experience**

Jan 2023 - PRESENT

### **The Burlap People** - Marketing and PR Head

- Develop and execute innovative marketing strategies to promote premium handcrafted bags to customers globally
- Manage social media accounts, including Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, LinkedIn, and YouTube, and increase brand engagement and followers
- Plan and coordinate events and promotional campaigns to increase brand visibility and sales
- Collaborate with graphic designers, content writers, and video editors to create engaging and compelling marketing content

- Conduct market research and analyze data to stay updated with current market trends and adjust marketing strategies accordingly
- Manage relationships with media outlets, influencers, and brand ambassadors to secure coverage and build relationships with the brand

Dec 2022 - Jan 2023

#### **Apeejay Oxford Bookstore, Park Street** - Creative Writing and Social Media Intern

- International Delegates Research and assembling data for Apeejay Kolkata Literature
  Festival
- Maintaning strict social media presence for brand through posts on Facebook, Instagram and Twitter for Apeejay Kolkata Literature Festival
- Content Writing for Live Social Media updates for Apeejay Kolkata Literature Festival on Facebook, Instagram and Twitter
- Live reel updates for Instagram for Apeejay Kolkata Literature Festival
- On floor work around the clock with Apeejay Kolkata Literature Festival Team for interviewing international authors and securing quotes.

## Skills

- SEO/SEM
- Social Media Marketing and Paid Social Media Advertising
- Graphic Design Skills (Canva and Photoshop)
- Video Editing Skills
- Product Shoot
- Podcasting (Audacity, Anchor Fm, Spotify Ads Studio)
- Content and Creative Copywriting
- Public Speaking
- Data Entry (MS Excel, Word, Powerpoint)
- Client Negotiation
- Decision Making and Problem Solving

ENGLISH: ✓ ✓ ✓

HINDI: ✓ ✓ ✓

BENGALI: ✓ ✓ ✓

FOREIGN LANGUAGE: N/A

#### Certification

May 2022 - PRESENT

#### NIHT, Kolkata

- Master Program in Digital Marketing
- Enrolled under Jain University
- A detailed encapsulation of each and every element of Digital Marketing.

### **Education**

June 2022 - Present

NIHT Infosolution Pvt. Ltd., Elgin Road - Master Program in Digital Marketing, (Program affiliated by Jain University, Bengaluru)

2019

Bhawanipur Education Society College, Kolkata - B.A. in English

Qualified with B.A. Honors in English Literature with 52.87% as an overall average.

2016

A.K. Ghosh Memorial School, Kolkata - Higher Secondary Examination

Qualified Higher Secondary Examination with 79.4% as an overall average.

2014

Narmada High School, Kolkata - Madhyamik Pariksha

Qualified Secondary Examination with 69.2% as an overall average.

2007 - 2014

Modern Art (affiliated by Pracheen Kalakendra) , Layelka Road – Diploma in Fine Arts (4th Year)

### **Awards**

Qualified and positioned 2nd in MOA (Mad over Ads) which was an event organised by NIHT Digital Marketing.

The event was based on Advertising and Branding via Digital platforms of different brands.